Optimal Fibers in the House!
Y'all know the number!
877-393-4448
Optimal Fibers so fast, so fine
Got another provider, leaving behind
Come on everybody, let's get online
30 a month, gonna blow your mind
Five or years don't hesitate
Like it in now, before it's too late
877-393-4448
Time to apply, see Optimal.com for details
I'm Jake Stouck, co-founder and CEO of Serval
We built Serval to automate the IT work that slows companies down
Onboarding, password resets, accessed applications
My laptop stopped working
While employees wait for help, their real work is put on hold
IT desperately wants to automate this work
And that's why they need Serval
You just tell Serval what you want to automate in plain English
And it's built!
No drag and drop workflows
No expensive consultants
Employees get unblocked and IT teams
Go from drowning in tickets to building what actually matters
With Serval, IT becomes the AI engine
Powering the entire company
This is a new way to run IT
We guarantee you'll automate 50% of all tickets
And we'll prove it to you in a free 4-week pilot
Go to serval.com slash tickets
That's S-E-R-V-A-L dot com slash tickets
This isn't the end of a fight, it's the start of one
Lioness, the critically acclaimed original series from Taylor Sheridan
Returns August 2nd only on Paramount Plus
In the new season, hidden networks, foreign operatives and personal betrayals collide
Meanwhile, Joe walks the line between duty and family
As unseen forces circle her world
Leaving her to reckon with the war that now reaches into every part of her life
Don't miss the new season of Lioness
starring Zoe Saldana, Michael Kelly, with Morgan Freeman and Nicole Kidman
Streaming August 2nd only on Paramount Plus
This isn't the end of a fight, it's the start of one
Lioness, the critically acclaimed original series from Taylor Sheridan
Is now streaming only on Paramount Plus
In the new season, hidden networks, foreign operatives and personal betrayals collide
Meanwhile, Joe walks the line between duty and family
As unseen forces circle her world
Leaving her to reckon with the war that now reaches into every part of her life
Don't miss the new season of Lioness
Starring Zoe Saldana, Michael Kelly, with Morgan Freeman and Nicole Kidman
Now streaming only on Paramount Plus
This podcast, it's accosted in touchstone production
I've talked a lot over the years about food in prison
I hate to even call it food, to tell you the truth
It was slop
On my very first full day in prison, it was a Friday
One of the Italians with whom I became very friendly, Pete Calabrese
Mentioned offhandedly that it's Friday, that means it's fish day
And I responded by saying, oh great, I love fish
And he said, oh, don't eat this fish
We call it sewer trout and it's not fit for human consumption
Well, he and I walked down to the chow hall together
And what I saw was something that I'll never forget
The guys in the chow line were slopping the slop onto your tray
But behind them were boxes, boxes of fish
And on the side of these boxes, every one of them
It was clearly marked Alaskan cod, product of China
Feed use only, not for human consumption
And that's what they were putting on our plates
I looked at Pete, he said, I told ya
And so I never, ever, ever ate the fish
I've also talked about another incident that happened about halfway through my sentence
Where every Wednesday night was so-called taco night
And excuse the filthy thing I'm gonna say
I once threw away the entire taco
And the warden saw me throw the whole thing away
And he said, in the old days you could get written up for that
And I responded, I've eaten ass that tasted better than this taco
What do you do if you can't eat the food?
If you won't eat the food?
If you shouldn't eat the food?
If the food is gonna make you sick?
I'm John Kiriakou
Welcome to Dead Drop
What Makes a Spy Tick?
This is episode 10 in our series
Doing Time Like a Spy
And as always, we thank you for listening
We thank you even more for liking, rating, reviewing
And commenting on the podcast on whatever platform you happen to be listening to it
Prison food is institutional food
That other institutional food laughs at
No, that's actually not true, it sneers at it
And with good reason
The prison authorities don't want to spend a single dollar more than they have to
Fold in a bunch of competing interests
Plenty of corruption and greed
And the result is a hellish jambalaya of gastronomic awfulness
There was one incident where for taco night, they accidentally fed us dog food
The reason we know that is that the warden, months after the fact, sent everybody a memo saying
Hey, sorry, but a couple of months ago on taco night, we accidentally fed you dog food
It's not our fault, the packaging was mixed up at the meat plant
Yeah
They labeled dog food as ground beef and they labeled the ground beef as dog food
The shame is not even that we were fed dog food
The shame is that we were fed dog food and we couldn't even tell the difference
So what did we do?
We relied on people like our guest tonight, Joey Castlell
Joey Castlell was one of the finest, I'm going to call him chefs at FCI Loretto
A lot of guys cook, the Mexicans all cook, right?
You have a trash can of water, you throw in a live electrical wire called a stinger
It immediately brings the water to a boil, you put some food in a plastic bag
Next thing you know, you've got a gourmet meal
The Mexicans ate to survive
We ate, and I say we, I'm including myself with the Italians
We ate as a culinary experience
Yes
Joey, welcome, good to have you
Thank you, John
Joey, walk us through this man
When I first saw a stinger, I unplugged it
I said, oh my God, what a health hazard
This is a live electrical wire, and the Mexicans are like, are you out of your mind?
We're making dinner
I didn't know what the heck they were doing
But then when you cooked, when Mark Lanzalotti cooked
It was like being in a restaurant in Little Italy
How did you do that? Walk us through it
Well, when I first came to the prison, let me say this real quick
I didn't know nothing about prison just like you
Sure
So I walked in, and this guy comes up to me
I forget his name, a black guy, and he says, what's your name, sir?
I said, Joey, and I'm thinking to myself, wow, nice people here
They're talking to me
So everybody's laughing, and I'm like, what are you laughing at?
He says, we'll tell you later, just keep talking to this guy
So I'm talking to him, he says, if there's anything you need, Joey, you let me know
And I said, okay
So then I go back to myself, three guys come in that were laughing
And I said, can you tell me why were you laughing?
He says, the guy is gay
He wants to pick you up right away because you're new in the prison
Well, the word got out to Peter Calabrese
When he found out, he said, Joey, stay away from them guys
If you find a Twinkie or a piece of gum or a lollipop on your bed, don't touch it
I said, okay, Pete, I won't
So I was learning little things here and there
And with the cooking, I knew how to cook on the outside with the stove
But like John said, the stinger
I knew what that was, so I bought one one day
Oh, you're kidding me, so you didn't know what a stinger was?
Watching, watching, everybody cook, I said, oh, okay
But the stuff they cooked was rice and the same things
Yeah, yeah
I cooked pizzas, I cooked managotti, I cooked spaghetti, meatballs
John, it was two o'clock in the morning, John sound asleep
I said, I'm hungry, I'm gonna cook
I made, I think I made a pizza or managotti, something I made Italian
So I crawled out, I walked to John's room
I said, John, John, he goes, yeah, I'm sleeping
I said, John, I got Italian food
He says Italian food and he got right up
I did, I did
And this went on consistently, we did it all the time
Yeah, how about the calzones you used to make?
Let me talk about the calzones for a second
So a lot of the Mexican guys used to cook
And like you said, it was rice, rice, rice, rice
With this cezon sauce, or not even sauce, it was like an orange powder
That had no flavor at all, but they sold it in the commissary
And so they would sell these, they would call them calzones
And Pete said to me one day, why do you buy those disgusting things?
And I said, oh, they're so filling and delicious
They got all kinds of stuff in them
He goes, it's not a calzone, it's a fucking burrito
Those guys wouldn't know a calzone if it walked up and introduced it itself to them
Yes
And so I said, you're right
And then you started making calzones and I said, oh my god
This is an actual calzone, like from an Italian restaurant
Made in a trash bucket, full of boiling water
But wait a minute, I don't know if you knew this
I never got, I got some of the stuff from commissary
I used to get it from the guards in the kitchen
Yes, I wanted to ask you about that
Yes
So I had a good hookup right there
Especially when I got with the, can we say names on here?
Sure, why not?
We'll believe you later if we have to
When I got with Nicky Carrazzo
Yes
I had to learn to hold nine yards
Yeah, because Nicky was a very, very important person
In a certain Italian-American subculture
Yeah
And very important person
And as his status demanded
He got the best of everything
Including the best food
Our friend Mark Lanzalotti, who was an absolutely brilliant cook
I once told him, he fed me
It was on my birthday, it was my 50th birthday
He had a big bash for me
I remember
Remember that?
I told my wife that night
It was the first time I had smiled in nine months
Yeah
And oh my god, how we laughed our heads off that night
But he made this gourmet meal
And the very first thing he did
And he did this every time he cooked
Is he would pull out all of his Tupperware
He would load the Tupperware with complete meals
And send them to Nicky and to Pete
And everybody else of that status
Yes
They had a crooked guard on payroll
Who was bringing in everything that we needed
You know, loaves of Italian bread
White wine for the Marsala sauce
We got pork loin
We got beautiful chicken breasts
And fresh tomatoes and fresh mushrooms
And onions and all kinds of stuff
But
Bags and bags of pasta and sauce
It wasn't just crooked guards bringing it in from the inside
From the outside rather
It was guards working in the kitchen
They're supposed to be guarding the prisoners that are cooking the food
They're actually stealing most of the food
Or stealing the good food
And then selling it to you
Well, yeah, that's how it works
And you know our money was books of stamps and mac rolls
Right
So whatever
Nicky wanted pasta that night
I go with books of stamps
Pull the guy aside and say, listen, we want this
We want this with this
Within 20 minutes it was in my room
When did you arrive, Joey?
So you got there just barely before I did
I got there February 28th, 2013
Yeah
So when I first arrived
I was there maybe a week or two weeks
And one of the guards in the kitchen was fired
And escorted out
And Pete told me it was because
He was allowing prisoners
Working in the cafeteria to steal food
And that was a very popular side hustle
They would just go from cell to cell to cell
Selling food for bags of mackerel or books of stamps
But he would allow them to steal the food
They would change for a blow job
That they would blow him
And then they could steal whatever food they wanted
Yeah
They walked that guy out
And they allowed him to keep his pension
Which was not cool at all
But then they tightened things up
And I remember they used to frisk us
As we would walk out of the cafeteria
Because God forbid you should have an apple
In your pocket
Or a pat of butter that you want to take back to yourself
How did you get around all that?
It was easy
It was just given to me all the time
I didn't have to walk out with nothing
All I had to do
They say, who is this for?
I said, Nicky
Go ahead
Done
Mm-hmm
And when I brought it to Nicky's room
I was looking for him one day, right?
He called Chris
You remember Chris?
Yes
Chris came down and said, Nicky wants you up there now to cook
It was 10 o'clock in the morning
I said, okay, I'll go start cooking the pasta
Well, I'm cooking, getting everything ready
The peppers, the onions
The oil, everything
So Nicky says, all right
Everybody out
I said, Nicky, you just called me up here to cook
I'm taking my hour nap
Get out and come back in an hour
So I had to put everything away
Come back and cook
Oh, my God
And when you were cooking in Nicky's room
It was the same as cooking in your own room
We're talking about a garbage bucket
Yeah
Full of hot water
Brand noodle
Everything he had was brand new
The Mexicans used their dirty bucket
The dirty
Yeah
At brand new
We actually used
There were four Mexicans in my first cell
Yeah
We actually used that bucket for trash
And then they would just pull the trash out, fill it with water
Throw the stinger in and make food
Right
It was disgusting
Yeah
Okay, so walk us through
How do you do this?
You got the bucket
You fill it with water
And then what?
While you're preparing everything
You'll put the stinger in
Tie it
And explain what a stinger is
A stinger is
Wires from an iron
Or
Yeah
Whatever they can get there
A lamp, yeah
And it's square pieces of metal
They would get it where the metal makers
They had like a shop in there
Yes, or they'd steal the faceplate
Off the wall
Yeah
So it was two pieces of metal
With something in the middle
So you don't get shocked
Well, I never got shocked
But let me tell you
Every time they raided us
They took my stinger
Yeah
And I said to the guard
I said
I just want to tell you
You know I cook for Nicky
Everybody in the prison knows
Okay
We won't take your stingers no more
So then
Other guards would come
They would take it
Because they didn't know
I had 26 stingers
After they let me had stingers
In my locker
And I had them on the shelf
Wide open
Nobody touched nothing
The respect we got
Because of Nicky
Yeah
And I would just like to
Go on
I want to say something
Before we get into anything else
When I first came into prison
Like I said
I didn't do nothing
I was sitting with the blacks
You know I had the black side
Right
We should say
In the cafeteria
All African American inmates
Sit on one side
Yeah
Every one of them
On the other side
It's divided
And we talked about this
In the past
The front table
Is what we call
The good guys
That's white guys
Most of them are Aryans
White guys
Convicted of crimes
That have nothing to do
With child sex crimes
The next table
Was Italians on the one side
And Native Americans on the other
And then behind them
Were all the pedophiles
And the rats
They had to sit together
Yeah
So go ahead
So I had colored guys
When I first came to prison
And myself
So they liked me
You know
Joke around
And I was the only Italian
Or white person
To say the N word to them
You know how they all say
I was the only one to say that
Anybody else
They would shank them
Yeah
They loved me
I'm that kind of person
Me and you bonded real quick
Immediately
Yeah
So anyway
They said you come sit with
I said okay
Now I don't know nothing
I see all these people
I'm there for like
Two weeks
Three weeks
Eating there all the time
So then finally
Nikki says
What are you doing
Sitting over there
I said Nikki
I just got here
I don't know much
He says for now on
You're over here
With the Gambino's
You're with us
Yes
I said okay
So then
I'm Pete Selly now
He says Joey
No, no, no, no
You're not with the Gambino's
You're with the Bananos
Yeah
And I said Pete
I don't know what's
Way to go now
I don't know
You know Pete said
The same thing to me
I was sitting with the Aryans
Only because the Aryans
Told me to
And then Pete said to me one day
We were walking out
Our cells were directly across
From each other
And we were walking out
And he said
Let me ask you something
Why do you sit with those Nazi
Retards in the cafeteria
Those were his exact words
And I said
I don't know Pete
When I first arrived
They told me sit with them
And then very dramatically
He puts his finger in the air
And he says
From today
You're with the Italians
And then I sat with the Italians
The whole rest of the time
I was there
When you first started
Sitting at the Italian tables
With us
Nikki would always go
I know he lives next door
To you across the hall
Is he all right
You sure Joe
He's all right
I said yeah
Nikki he's good
I vouch for him
He's good
You don't know the stuff
He asks me about you
I believe it
Because he asked
Mark Lanzalotti
Exactly the same question
He was genuinely worried
Because the guy
Didn't know the difference
Between the CIA
And the FBI
Right
And he was afraid
That I was a cop
Yeah
He said
The FBI are cops and rats
The CIA protected us
From the Muslims
That's what he told them
Yeah
And then I was okay after that
I said he's a good guy
Nikki he's a good guy
He says all right then
He's with us
I said all right
We're made men now Johnny
Seriously right
I felt like I was
Yeah
I'll tell you man
That was a community
The Italians
I say all the time
That the Italians
In prison for stupid reasons
Are considered to be a gang
They even have their own suffix
On the prisoner number 047
If you're 047
That means you're mob
And it's not fair
Right
But anyway
It's not a gang
Anyway let's pretend
For a moment that it is
Right
Of all the prison gangs
And these are major gangs
You got the Crips
And the Bloods
And the Latin Kings
And the Boracchos
And the Norteños
And the MS-13
And this one
And that one
And the other one
The Italians were the smallest
And the most highly respected
Yes
And that was
Hands down
There were no exceptions to that
The Italians were universally respected
And another thing too
The Italians were the only gang
In air quotes
That didn't have a shot collar
And they didn't have a shot collar
Because they didn't need a shot collar
You had made men
At any given time
There were six, seven, eight of them
And they did everything by consensus
And we would all have to sit with them
With the made men
And if something was to go on
If somebody wanted to beat somebody up
Or everybody would agree
That's how it worked in there
That's right
That's exactly right
I genuinely liked and respected them
Yeah
I'll tell you a funny thing too
I was an expert witness in a trial
Last week
I was an expert witness for the defense
And this poor guy
Was charged with six felonies
All six of which
Carried a mandatory sentence of life
Without parole
And I testified on his behalf
He had a public defender
And in the cross-examination
All the U.S. attorney wanted to ask me about
And he was mean about it
And aggressive
All he wanted to ask me about
Was the Italians at Loretto
And that was I with the Italians
I said you bet I was
And you said that they were honorable
And I said and they were honorable
They're all convicted murderers
I said I don't know what they were convicted of
It was none of my business
I can tell you that in my dealings with them
They were all honorable to a man
Every single one of them
In fact I'm still friends with a lot of them
Because they were honorable
And so in the end
I'm very very proud to say this
The guy was found not guilty
On all six counts last week
Yeah all six counts
That doesn't happen very often
But anyway
I wanna get back to cooking
You've got this pipeline
Of real food
Actual food
Well it's not like you're sitting in your
In your bunk
Reading out of a cookbook
So how did you know what to make
How did you know how to plan
What to make
And what do you do
If you're halfway through a meal
And you're like oh crap
I don't have any tomatoes
Or mushrooms
Or chicken breast
Or whatever
What do you do?
I always had it
We always had it
I never was out nothing
I don't know what to say
It was there
Whatever we needed
Just like the movie Goodfellows
That's how we
Yeah I say that all the time Joe
That scene in Goodfellows
Was one thousand percent true
We gave the guvarios
Even the garlic
And that it liquefies
In the oil
And they ran that scene
Because it was true
And that's how we cooked
Every single day
And I'll tell you what
The Mexicans would use their ID cards
To cut
We had razor blades
Yeah
I remember you
Every month
For the prisoners who were too poor
To afford
Commissary
They would give you a
What did they call it
The bag
To keep yourself clean
They had a name for it
Anyway
It included a disposable single edge razor
And I remember you breaking
You're very strong
I should add
I mean we're all ten years older now
But you're very strong
And I remember you breaking open
The single blade razor
And taking the blade out
And then using the blade
To cut the garlic
That's how I started with the blade
I don't know this guard's name
I forget his name
White guy
He had long hair
Oh I remember him
He was a cool guy
I liked him
Yeah I remember him
Walk by
I heard the keys and the chains
I said hide my stinger
He says no Joe it's just me
You don't have to hide it
So he saw me with the little blade
You cut yourself with it
Yeah
He says wait till tomorrow
I had packages of big razor blades
Unbelievable
I said are you telling me to go
Wack somebody or something
Oh you cooked with this
I liked him
So with booking
It just comes to my mind
I can't even explain it
I mean if I wake up in a
Nicky wanted pasta
Or whatever
I would make the homemade sauce
I mean they would bring me
Yeah Kansas tomatoes
The paste
Olive oil
It was amazing
And I'll tell you what
If I didn't have nowhere to live
Like these bums at love prison
I would have stayed
I would have stayed in there
Tell you the truth
Cause if you ever go to prison
I know you don't want to go to prison
But if you ever do anybody
Federal prison
Go to federal prison
Yeah go to federal prison
I remember
I've said this
I'm going to say another
Not very nice word
But I remember three guys
Sitting in the TV room
Playing cards one day
It was the middle of the day
So everybody was away at work call
I had a no show job
Thanks to the Italians
I walked in there for some reason
And they were playing cards
And they were in between hands
So the dealer was
Shuffling the cards
And one guy put his hands behind his head
He kind of kicks back and stretches
He looks around and he says
I got a warm bed
I got free medical care
I got TV
I got three meals a day
No bills
He said
If we had pussy
This would be paradise
And I remember thinking
Oh man
You've been inside too long buddy
But
They weren't even eating
Like the Italians were eating
We got to the point Joey
And I'm sure you remember this
My sentence was short
I was in 23 months
The last six or eight months
That I was in
I never went to the cafeteria
Yeah I never did either
There was no reason to
Only on certain things
Like a pizza's words
Pizza's
One night a week was pizza
One night a month was pizza night
Yeah
And let me tell you
We had trays and trays of pizza
Trays they brought out
When Nikki was there
They brought out a whole big
It was like a pizza tray
With pizza stacked
Everybody's looking at us like
Wow
Yeah
We didn't have dough
That's the only thing we didn't have
Pizza dough
Yeah
So we would use the wraps
You know the big wraps
The Mexicans would use
So I said
Let me think of something here
These wraps are kind of small
Maybe it looks like a single pizza
So I would lay four or five of them down
And it would come out to a big pizza
A large pizza
So with the garlic
I would chop the garlic
Like on good fellows
Yeah
And I had a piece of metal
And you would put olive oil on the metal
It was like a little cup
And it would heat up
And you would put the garlic in it
And it would cook it
It would saute it
And the sauce
I did the same
I used the cans of tomatoes
I heated it up
You put it in a plastic bag
You put it in the water
You tie the bag
You close the bag
And it steams
And let me tell you
The smell from my food
Everybody would come to my cell
If I was going to sell it in there
For cash
I'd have been rich today
Yes
The whole prison smelled like it
Joey's cooking
But let me tell you
Sometimes I did sell stuff
I said, let me sell stuff too
Your line just went down
The scramble starts
Clipboards, binders, phone calls
Every minute down costs money
And most unplanned breakdowns are preventable
MaintainX helps you catch the failure
Before it happens
With easy to manage preventative maintenance
And work orders that can be created
And assigned in seconds
No binders
No excel
No scramble
Companies on MaintainX
Have cut unplanned downtime
By over 30%
Try it free at MaintainX.com
If you're enjoying Dead Drop
And, of course, we hope you are
Then, while you're waiting for new episodes
I'd like to suggest another great
Granular Story podcast
From the Costard & Touchstone family
Just the photographer with David Swanson
Does for photojournalism
What Dead Drop does for spies
Pulitzer Prize-winning photojournalist
David Swanson tells you stories
His amazing news photos just can't
What it felt like
Being in all those dangerous places
Like war zones and natural disasters
Doing his job taking pictures
Having been to a few war zones myself
I can tell you this
Just the photographer will put you right there
On the ground, right next to David
Inside his head, in fact
It's a hell of a podcast
And you can find it wherever you find
Your favorite podcasts
Or at costardandtouchstone.com
There's a link in this episode's show notes
In fact, you'll find lots of great story podcasts
At costardandtouchstone
Like The Donor
A DNA horror story
The Hall Closet
Sage Wellness Within
And the how not to make a movie podcast
Who knows, your next favorite podcast
Might be just a click away
Now, back to Dead Drop
I was next to a cell
If you come out of your cell
And your cell is to your back
And I'm on the right in front of you
The guys on the left in front of you
They were mostly Mexicans
And their hustle
Their hustle was to steal meat
From the cafeteria
They mostly stole chicken
And then they would go sell the cell
Everyday selling chicken
Or selling eggs
They sold a lot of eggs
In fact, they would put it
Exactly, exactly
They would put it in plastic bags
So is that how you got your meat too
Was it just from the cops in the kitchen
Or were you getting outside meat as well?
I wasn't getting it from any
From the guys in there
I was getting it from either the guards
Or the prisoners that worked for the guards
So they have good stuff
That's what I thought
Beef, turkey
As soon as I got it, I put it on ice
So it was good
I remember a lot of guys
Having those scrawny bony chickens
From the chow hall
And just keeping it on ice
And then cooking it in the afternoons
We didn't eat those bony
You could really get a broth
Spread it up and make something
I don't know what they mean
I used to sell my chicken
We got chicken like every Tuesday
At lunch or whatever it was
I used to sell my chicken for a bag of tuna
To some guy that was like
On this protein only diet
He was trying to work out and build muscle
And he would buy my nasty chicken
Every week
He'd buy the tray
Yeah, he'd buy the tray, exactly
And then I'd go back to my place
And eat your food
Or go to Mark's and eat his food
Yeah, we had some big bowls of food
I remember the parties
Everybody bring your bowl
Joey, I used to say
I gained 35 pounds in prison
35 pounds
I remember you and I talking about it
Because you showed me a picture of yourself one time
And it was like Mr. Olympus
Mr. America competition
And then all of a sudden we got these bellies
From all the pasta we're eating
And the warden said to me one time
He said, hey, you're sure putting on a lot of weight
I said, what are you, my tailor or my warden?
Yeah
And then he walked away
The only thing I didn't want to make in there
Was the hooch
No, I never messed with it
No, I wasn't smoking cigarettes
I wasn't doing nothing
You'd go to the hole for three months
For that something stupid
Yeah, not worth it
I remember the hooch
It was mostly the Native Americans would make it
They would steal fruit from the cafeteria
And then ferment the fruit
And make moonshine out of it
A couple of the black guys did too
They would hide it in the drop ceiling
Of the TV room
So that it wasn't tied to any one person
But do you remember
They found hooch in the drop ceiling
During the NBA playoffs
Yeah
So they shut the TVs off
That was the punishment
Everybody got punished
Nobody was allowed to watch basketball for the week
Well, I don't know if you remember this
Somebody hid the hooch somewhere
And it was the bag popped
And I don't know if it was the warden's office
Or somebody's office
That worked there
That was high ranked
All the hooch went down in that person's office
Oh my God
I don't remember that
It might have been before you came
The whole place got locked down
But they found out who did it
But imagine how stupid that person was
To put it over
Yeah, that's really stupid
And the people who made the hooch
Are the people who had long sentences
Because of what they didn't care
Yeah, they didn't care
And it was like the guys that just
Had to have a cigarette
I know I'm getting off the subject of food
But the guards in violation of all the rules
Would chew tobacco
And then they would just dig into their lip
And fling the tobacco onto the ground
And guys would collect the chewed tobacco
Dry it out
Roll it in toilet paper
And then sell it for a Mac
And people would smoke previously chewed
Chewing tobacco rolled in toilet paper
Because they so desperately had to have a cigarette
Gross
I was a heavy smoker with cigarettes
I didn't smoke nothing in there
But the minute I got out
I don't know, I bought a pack
So how, you've got a successful restaurant right now
A successful pizzeria
You post on Facebook pictures of your beautiful food
Yeah
How different is it now from when it was in there?
Well different as I can walk out to the refrigerator
And I ask nobody except my wife, she's the boss too so
But it's just
It was a
A really experience in there
But me and you and the rest of the guys
We had a good
We had a good in there
Yeah
I hate to say that
You know, people ask me every once in a while
If I miss it
And I say absolutely not
I don't miss anything about it at all
Nothing
Yeah
But then, you know, when I'm sitting here with Joey
Or I'm sitting with Mark Lanzalotti
Good times
Or Grant, yeah we actually
We made it okay for each other
Yeah
I used to go down to Mark's cell almost every night
Because he was cooking every single night
And of course he would give me
Just like you did
Two or three times more food than I could possibly eat
Yeah
And so I'd eat until I was full
And then I'd go for the second seating two hours later
And eat again
And put on those 35 pounds
But the food was so good
I told you this and I told Mark
That I would spend $35 for this
In an Italian restaurant outside
That's how good it was
You, more than Mark, made desserts on top of it
How in the world did you make dessert?
And what desserts did you make?
I made cannolis one time for him
He couldn't believe it
He thought, where'd you get these from?
The outside?
I said, no, Nicky
They had these little cookies in commensari
But they looked like a shell
And it looked like an Italian pastry
Yeah
So I said, let me see what I need for this now
I gotta ask the guard
So I need a heavy whipping cream
Some kind of cheese
And I don't know, something else
Within, I say a day or two
He brought it to me
And I just, I put it there
I would taste it
And I just taste like cannoli
So that made the cannolis
Amazing
We made cakes, remember the cakes we made?
The cakes, I remember that
John, the cakes we made
They were like store-boughtin' cakes
They were, they were like store-boughtin' cakes
You made a flourless cake one time
It was like a lemon cake or something like that
That was ridiculous
I was like, dude, you made this in a garbage pail?
We even got lemons
And we even got lemons
You made lemon cake from scratch
Have you adapted any of those crazy
Those crazy recipes to what you're doing now?
Not really, no
That actually wouldn't make sense
It would be kind of depressing
I tell you, I go on TikTok sometimes
And I see these people that just got out of prison
And they're showing their family
This is how we, and they're cooking
Just like they, he would have a stinger and everything
I wouldn't ever do that
Bring that outside and do that
You know what I mean?
He would kitchen at home
With a stinger and a plastic bag and the garbage pail
I don't want to go that
That's nuts
Yeah, you don't want to do that
But not to change the subject
But I just got to say, again
When I first walked into prison
Two guys came to my room
One was Chris and I don't know who the other one was
Nikki wants to see you
I said, okay
So I walked up to Nikki's room
There was like four or five guys
I said, oh man, to myself, what's going on?
Well, Nikki says, sit down on this chair
I sat down
Now the guys are standing here
Nikki's behind me
All of a sudden he puts his hand on my head
And he goes like this
He goes, I said to myself
I said, I think I'm going to get something shanked
Or something's wrong
Should I run or what should I do?
He goes, you're lucky I like you, Joey
You're lucky I like you
I said, Nikki, whew
Yeah, it was crazy stuff that went on there
Yeah, he was a very important
And very scary guy
One of the things that I learned really quickly
Hanging out with the Italians
Is you never ever wanted somebody to say about you
You believe this fucking guy
Then you knew you were on the list
Yeah, yeah
No, you never wanted to be this fucking guy
Who was Nikki's cellmate, the old guy?
Yeah, I remember it was
Oh, I can't really
Gait
I just, I don't know, I can't remember
Gaitano was his name
He went by Gait
The old guy
Yeah, the old guy
Gait, remember Jake?
Sure
The old man, let me tell you a quick story
He was going back, he had life
Yes
He was a high ranked mobster too
Upstate New York
Yeah
That life
So one day, we're all in a room
He says, guys, I'm going back to court
I'm gonna overturn my life
We're like, now he's 72 years old saying this
Jake, we're so proud of you, all right
Let us know what happens
So he goes to court, comes back
He goes, I did it
They overturned my life
They gave me 50 years
I remember that
We all, we all
Yay
Only 50 years
Like a fake
Hey, there was one guy from Upstate
I won't say his name
He asked me if I would write his appeal
He had 30 years
Yeah
I said, sure, let me see your case papers
And we'll figure something out, I'll write your appeal
But listen, I did what they convicted me of doing
I killed a guy
Don't get me wrong, he says
If I could, I'd dig him up and kill him again
30 years, it's not reasonable
I was like, oh man, that's not the right attitude
Eight, seven, seven, three, nine, three
Four, four, four, five, I'm so fast, so fine
Got another provider, leaving behind
Thirty a month, gonna blow your mind
Five, oh years, don't hesitate
Like it in now, before it's too late
Eight, seven, seven, three, nine, three, four, eight
Time's up live
See optimum.com for details
Back to school is busy enough
The last thing you need is shopping that makes it harder
Whether you're moving into a dorm, your first department
Or just getting organized for the semester
Wayfair makes it easy to get everything you need in one place
Furniture, bedding, storage, decor
Study essentials, all at prices you'll love
With fast shipping before move-in day
Get everything you need for back-to-school season
Shop Wayfair.com today
Wayfair, every style, every home
What's next for you?
You've got the pizzeria
You've moved, actually, you lived in Connecticut
Yeah, Connecticut
You moved down in North Carolina
So what's next?
I'm older now, 58 years old
I just turned that June 27th
I'm gonna stay here
I have a wonderful wife
My mom has dementia
I'm sorry
He lived here, so that's why I came down
Because something was wrong with her
We didn't know what it was
Then I came down and found out she had dementia
Book her in with me
I will not put her in a home, John
No, you're a good son
And we live here now
I do my very best, I'm the only child
So she took care of me all them years
That's right
I forgot you were an only child
Now it's my turn
But I'm happy to be out
In New York, Connecticut
Here is so peaceful
North Carolina is nice
Very nice
Oh, wait a minute, John
You know what we forgot?
You're silly
I don't know if we could bring that up
Which one?
Oh, that crazy guy
The Afghan?
John
Oh, my God
You gotta do something with this guy
So John, just go out to the yard
His name was Cher
He had his arm blown off
By an IED in Afghanistan
This guy was certifiably insane
Any psychiatrist in America
Would have certified him as insane
Yeah
Because we knew he was insane
We plotted to push him over the edge
Just to get him transferred to another prison
And be rid of him
You were a major part of that operation
My bunkie was Frank Russo
He was the auditor general of Cuyahoga County, Ohio
And he was actually arrested
While he was running for governor of Ohio
He would have won
Frank was a natural politician
But Frank said something
When you and I finally pushed him over the edge
And he lost his mind
They took him to solitary
And then they sent him to another prison
Frank said, thank God
We finally got him into solitary
Because I was going to take a poop in his boots
Yeah
And he meant it literally
He was literally going to poop in the guy's boots
You did something to him
That was so funny
That 11 years later
I still laugh about it
When I think about it
Now the story, John
You say it better
Oh my God
So this guy was nothing but trouble
He had no respect for anybody's property
He had no respect for anybody's space or time
You remember how hot it was
In our housing unit
Because we had no windows
And so they had these gigantic fans
And he would just like
Pull his pants down
And air out his balls
In front of the giant fan
And we're like, dude
You're going to get shanked
Doing that
Right?
Mutity is unacceptable in prison
And you're just standing there
Airing out your balls
So we started doing things
Just messing with him
And making a long story short
What you came up with
Was so friggin' hilarious
He was a very, very pious Shia Muslim
I mean it's kind of a disconnect
Being very, very religious
And being very, very child molester
Right
So, yeah, it's incongruous
Who could explain it?
So anyway, he had this prayer rug
That was his pride and joy
It was like the only possession
That he cared about
John, I used to get sick of him
Seeing him kneeling on that rug
Choke him every day, John
John, and you were so upset
I said, John, we got to do something to this guy
I said, go to the yard
I'll take care of this, John
Okay
You did
You took care of it
You made me look completely innocent
Because it was out of the yard
Everybody thought that I was the one doing this stuff
And I was doing a lot of it
But what really pushed him over the edge was you
So the guards were watching me
They were going to catch me
Torturing this guy
Figuratively speaking
I went out to the yard
To kill time and walk around
And you...
Locker first
Yeah, you stole everything out of his locker
All of his candies
All of his food
His diet cokes
You stole everything
So he opened the locker
And it's just empty
He lost his mind
Number one
Then you wrote a giant
Erect dick
On the prayer rug
Sharpie
And so he tore the bottom
It was on the bottom
The bottom was just plain
It was like a non-slip surface
He tore it off and threw it away
And then he said something that was so odd to me
He said, at least they didn't draw an asshole
There's nothing worse than the human asshole
Nothing is filthier than the human asshole
Well, that's all he had to say
So I told you
And then the next time he went out to play soccer
You wrote on it
Asshole you are
And then you wrote underneath Yoda
Yeah
I don't know what stuff like that
After John
Before we killed him
Yeah, we were gonna kill him
And then he finally lost his mind
I ran down to the unit manager's office
And I said
I said, Cher's having a mental breakdown
So he called
Well, the cops, SIS
They ran up
You could hear the keys jingling from a quarter mile away practically
And somebody from medical
And they cuffed him
He was screaming, swearing
He was gonna fuck our mothers
He was gonna fuck our sisters
He was gonna fuck us up the ass
He's gonna shove his fist up our asses
And that was the last I heard of him
He was just screaming, screaming these obscenities
So they transferred him, right?
They got him out of town
Yeah, they got him
They transferred him out before I left
Yeah, that's a way
And what really pissed
He had these two cousins
Or a cousin and a brother-in-law
They would come like every week and visit him
And nobody told them that he wasn't in the prison anymore
And these guys drove up
And came all the way to the prison
From Washington
And they were like, yeah, he doesn't live here
Where is he?
New Jersey, maybe, I don't know
Oh, those guys were so mad
That's in the book too, isn't it?
Yeah
The book, right?
Oh, man, we made his life miserable
Yeah, I couldn't take that guy no more
We had to get him out
We had to
For our own mental health, we had to get him out
Even the Muslims
Would not allow him to pray with them
Right
He was nuts
And he was judgmental
And he was cruel
And he would call
Because most of the Muslims are black Muslims
They're converts
And he would call them fake Muslims
Oh, yeah, I remember
Yeah
And you're gonna tell these
Totally ripped, stacked, giant black guys
That they're fake Muslims
And they don't know what they're doing
And they're gonna destroy them
And do you remember what we finally did
Or you did
You put pork salami under his pillow
Oh, yeah
Yes
Wait, you cut it
You cut it, I remember
I did, I cut it
I cut it into slices
And we laid it out under his pillow
And it was there all day
And it was so hot
In the summer we didn't have air conditioning
So it was like 90 degrees in there
We used to soak our bath towels in water
Yeah
And lay on our beds with a wet bath towel
Just to try to cool off
So that salami was cooking
Fermenting all day under his pillow
And I remember after he freaked out
And they took him to solitary
These black Muslims came to the cell
And they stood at the entrance
And the stain from the salami
Was on the pillow in the sheets
And one of them said
They'd done him in with the swine
Yeah
Honest to God, if it wasn't for Joey
And Mark and Pete
I'm not sure how I could have gotten through it
Yeah, because when you came in everybody was like
Oh, the CIA, the cops
Don't go near that guy
The first like four weeks
I kept my distance, I kept my mouth shut
And I went to get a haircut
And Pete was in there
Getting a haircut
Yep
And I just started making small talk with him
And he said to me
Listen, I gotta tell ya
I know who you are
And you carry yourself far better
Than I expected you would
And I said I appreciate that
I was trying to be as tough as I could
I said truth be told
I'm not afraid of anybody
Which was bullshit of course
But I said I'm not afraid of anybody
And he said good, keep that up
We were friends from then on
I still talk to Nicky's main guy there
George, I don't know if you remember George
I remember George well
With that raspy voice
I talk to him all the time
Excellent
And I'm in constant touch with Mark
And with Brett
Which came up in that trial the other day
Well, you brag that you're still in touch
With members of organized crime
And I said yes, I am
And they're good and honorable men
Which was not the response they expected
They expected me to say no, no, no
That was a lifetime ago
I said yeah, I talk to them all the time
And they're dear friends
And then I turned to the jury
Oh, I'm so proud of myself
I turned to the jury
And I said there was a crooked congressman from Ohio
Named Nye
N-Y-E
He was in prison in Ohio
Federal prison on a corruption charge
He did 23 months just like I did
When he got out of prison he said
Nobody goes to prison to make friends
But the friends that I made in prison
Are lifelong friends
That was true
There are a lot of people in prison who are innocent
There are a lot of people in prison who are guilty
But who don't deserve to be in prison
There are a lot of people in prison who are good
And decent people
And those are my friends
And as I hope you now agree
One of those very good and decent people
Is my friend Joey
Thank you again for sitting in with me, Joey
I think I owe you dinner
A really good one
In our next episode we'll get back to the prison grind
As my out date approaches
I've got more reason than ever to keep my head down
But, you know, it's still prison
Prison rule is still applied
Unfinished business that needed attending to
A whistleblowing federal prisoner's got to do
What a whistleblowing federal prisoner's got to do
Until then, please don't forget to like, rate, review
Or comment on the podcast
It really does help
Until next time, I'm John Kiriakou
Dead Drop is written by John Kiriakou and Alan Katz
Costart and Touchstone Productions produces the podcast
And John Kiriakou, Alan Katz and Nick Mechanic
Are its executive producers
His podcast, it's a costume and touchstone production
Your line just went down
The scramble starts, clipboards, binders, phone calls
Every minute down costs money
And most unplanned breakdowns are preventable
MaintainX helps you catch the failure before it happens
With easy to manage preventative maintenance
And work orders that can be created and assigned in seconds
No binders, no excel, no scramble
Companies on MaintainX have cut unplanned downtime
By over 30 percent
Try it free at MaintainX.com
Back to school is busy enough
The last thing you need is shopping that makes it harder
Whether you're moving into a dorm, your first department
Or just getting organized for the semester
Wayfair makes it easy to get everything you need in one place
Furniture, bedding, storage, decor, study essentials
All at prices you'll love
With fast shipping before move-in day
Get everything you need for back-to-school season
Shop Wayfair.com today
Wayfair, every style, every home
This message is brought to you by Colaguard
If you recorded songs off the radio for a mixtape
It might be time to scream for colon cancer
The Colaguard test is non-invasive
Requires no special prep or time off
And you start screening right from your home
It's just three simple steps
Setup, sample, and ship
If you're 45 or older and at average risk
Ask your doctor about the Colaguard test
Available by prescription only
Learn more or request a prescription
at colaguard.com slash podcast